Omer Ali Abdallh

Front End Developer

Q Dubai, United Arab Emirates
 ■ Omeralis2000@gmail.com
 L +971585906465

Profile

Having 5 years of IT experience in Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) preparation requirements. Front-end infrastructure development using HTML5, CSS3, SCSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, Ajax, TypeScript, Responsive design, good experiences in developing and Angular and ReactJS framework for single page application and other design library based on JavaScript. Highly skilled in back-end and create web services components for restful web services to interact with user interfaces and Call REST APIs and manipulate complex JSON.



Front-end Frameworks and Libraries

HTML5,CSS3,SCSS, Tailwind CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, TypeScript.
Angular & ReactJS Frameworks, Responsive design.

Version control

Git on GitHub, GitLab & Microsoft Teams, Azure DevOps

SQL & MySQL and Oracle Database

uı ux

Adobe XD and Figma

Professional Experience

Jan 2018 – present Khartoum, sudan **Sabq Charity Organization,** Software Developer Provide technical support to the organization

Aug 2019 – Jan 2022 Khartoum, Sudan Oasis computer System, Front end Developer ☑

- Worked on the architecture and development of an insurance aggregator application providing service to more than 5000 clients.
- Worked on the architecture and development of dashboards and control panels for the customers to manage and keep track of their products and services provided by them.
- Worked on developing and implementing of a fully integrated web-based insurance broker system to replace the existing desktop version.
- Maintained and refactored legacy applications, improving their performance by more than 30%
- Building new Angular components for the customer-facing web app.
- Interfaced with 5 customers per month to gather requirements and resolve issues.
- Presided over a 30% increase in repeat business.

Nov 2018 – Aug 2020 Khartoum, Sudan Afromony, Full Stack Developer 🗷

- Developing electronic payment system (Morsal Core) and solving problems, in addition to developing websites and electronic payment systems.
- Implemented the Integration with customers that provide online payments services (Restful APIs).
- Worked on the architecture and development of dashboards and control panels.

Feb 2019 – Jul 2020 Khartoum, Sudan Antalya Company, Full Stack Developer

- Worked on the architecture and development of a web-based Medical Consultant Broker.
- Designed, analyze and implementing the dashboard for the Medical Consultant Broker.
- Creating and maintaining the server-side API.

Jan 2018 – Feb 2019 Khartoum, Suadn **Sudan University of Science and Technology - Admission and Registration Deanship,** Admission and Registration Deanship (Department of Card)

Mar 2021 Khartoum, Sudan

Specialized Medical Insurance Company, Front-End Development Part Time

Education

Mar 2013 – Dec 2017 Bachelor's degree in Management Information System,

Khartoum, Sudan University of Science and Technology

Omer Ali Abdallh 1/2

Projects

Morsel Payment (CMS), Afromoney

Development and maintain of a web-based payment report system for Morsal Core.

Salary App, Afromoney

Online batch payment system that provides an easy way to pay for multi beneficiaries.

Worked on designing and implement the front-end and back-end.

Medical Insurance System, Afromoney

Consist of two applications for Khartoum State Health Insurance Authority that help the service providers and insured. A web-based application to help the service providers to keep track and manage their claims payments. Also, an application for the insured members to help them get the services from providers and pay for these services using his electronic payment card.

Worked on designing, analyze and implementing the front-end and back-end.

Stock Management System, Point of Sale system

HR System, Employee life management system and everything related to financial aspects

Applus Insurance Aggregator - KSA, Insurance Brokerage Aggregator 🖸

Development of a fully integrated web-based insurance broker aggregator, to help the customers get the quotations, compare and buy online policies for their vehicles, travels, and medical malpractice. Worked on designing and implement the front-end.

AlMamoon Insurance Aggregator - KSA, Insurance Brokerage Aggregator

Development of a fully integrated web-based insurance broker aggregator, to help the customers get the quotations, compare and buy online policies for their vehicles, travels, and medical malpractice. Worked on designing and implement the front-end.

Insurance Broker System (IBS) - KSA, Insurance Broker System 🗹

Development of a fully integrated web-based insurance broker system to replace the existing desktop version.

Worked on designing and implement the front-end.

Concord-Aggregator-UI-Admin - KSA, Admin dashboard Concord Aggregator Insurance ☐ Development of a fully integrated web-based insurance broker aggregator, to help the broker keep track of all clients quotations, policies, claims, requests and complaints. Worked on designing and implement the front-end.

Applus-Aggregator-UI-Admin - KSA, Admin dashboard Applus Aggregator Insurance Development of a fully integrated web-based insurance broker aggregator, to help the broker keep track of all clients quotations, policies, claims, requests and complaints. Worked on designing and implement the front-end.

Manasaty -UAE, Landing Page ☐ introduction page for Manasaty

B-Al Halal -Kuwait

Dating and chatting site

References

Eng. Muizz Mohammed Mahdy, *Software Engineer*, Oasis Computer Systems Muizzmahdy@gmail.com, +971567227189

Eng. Akram Gorashi Sayed, *Software Engineer*, Oasis Computer Systems akramgorashi6@hotmail.com, +971585799622

Eng. Tariq Mansour, *Technical Department Manager*, Afromony +249912356709

Eng. Issara Mohmmed, *General Director*, Sabg Organization +249123273808

Omran Ibrahim, *Team Manager*, Oasis Computer System omranibrahim30@gmail.com, +249993061298

Eng. Yassin Eltaype, *Team Manager*, Oasis Computer System +971585966304

Omer Ali Abdallh 2/2